

DHIMAN TALAPATRAFull Stack Developer





Full Stack Engineer with **Cloud Development** experience. **10+** years of industry experience in delivering solutions for Banking and Telecom Domain across multiple technologies including CI/CD, UX, Cloud etc Technologies. **AWS Developer Associate**, **CSM Scrum Master** certified, having experience in managing and collaborating with various teams to deliver on time solutions.

+91 9874380099

■ dhiman.talapatra@gmail.com

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/dhiman-talapatra

WORK EXPERIENCE

Jul 2018 - Present Cognizant Technology solutions

Senior Associate

Offshore Lead / Scrum Master of 11-member team, Occasional Academy Trainer, Full Stack Developer, Cloud developer, UX developer, Automation Lead

Dec 2014 - Jun 2018 Cognizant Technology solutions

Associate

Offshore Lead of 5-member team, Occasional Academy Trainer, Full Stack developer, UX developer

Jul 2014 - Oct 2014 HCL Technologies Limited

Lead Engineer

Team lead of 3-member team, Full stack Java Developer

Oct 2012 - Jun 2014 HCL Technologies Limited

Software Engineer

Full Stack Java Developer, Selenium automation developer

Feb 2011 - Oct 2012 Infosys Limited

Senior Systems Engineer

Java developer in Finacle Banking solution

Feb 2010 - Jan 2011 Infosys Limited

Systems Engineer

Junior Java developer in Finacle Banking solution

SKILLS

Cloud

AWS, OpenShift3, Heroku, Flrebase

DevOps

Jenkins, Git-Lab CI/CD, Heroku Pipeline

Containerization

Docker, Kubernetes

Java

Core Java, Spring, JSF

Front-End

Angular, React, Bootstrap CSS

Mobile

Android, PWA

Other Languages

Kotlin, Python, Unix Shell Script

Big Data

Hadoop

CERTIFICATIONS

Nov 2020 AWS Certified Developer - Associate (DVA)

Amazon Simple Queue Service, Amazon DynamoDB, Amazon ElastiCache, Amazon Kinesis, AWS Lambda, Amazon API Gateway, AWS Elastic Beanstalk, AWS Identity and Access Management, AWS Key Management Service.

Jun 2019 CSM Certified Scrum Master

Agile Methodology, Roles and responsibilities of scrum master ,Various SCRUM parameters and measures, SCRUM ceremonies.

Mar 2019 Knowledge Stalwarts

Recognition of excellence in training and consistent high feedback from training participants.

Oct 2018 Full Stack Engineer

Angular (Angular material), Docker, Spring Boot (Secure REST PI with token based authentication), MySQL

Jul 2014 Hadoop and BIG data

concepts of Hadoop Distributed File System and MapReduce, Setup a Hadoop Cluster, Understand Data Loading Techniques using Sqoop and Flume, Perform Data Analytics using Pig and Hive, Work on a Real Life Project on Big Data Analytics and gain Hands on Project Experience

EDUCATION

2005 - 2009

Graduation - B.TECH - Electronics & Instrumentation Guru Nanak Institute of Technology, Sodepur

2003 - 2005

Senior Secondary - Science ST Xavier's Institution, Panihati

2002 - 2002 Secondary

Douglas Memorial High School, Barrackpore

PERSONAL INFO

Date of BirthGenderNationalityMarital Status30th April 1987MaleIndianMarried

Address

43/B Rabindrapalli Netaji Road, Barrackpore, Kolkata-700122.

Languages Known

Bengali, English, Hindi

Blood Group

Α+

Passport Number

H6701325